Guide to the Spanish Civil War Poster Collection ALBA.GRAPHICS.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Spanish Civil War Poster Collection
1936-2003
1936-1939
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
ALBA.GRAPHICS.001
234 items
This collection is comprised of two separate, but related, groups of Spanish Civil War posters held by the Tamiment Library. Although the two groups are stored separately, and are of different provenance, their closely related contents warranted bringing them together in a single collection guide. Series I: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, 1936-2003: The core group of posters in this group came to the Tamiment Library as part of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Collection, which was acquired by New York University in 2001. Other posters have been donated since, and the collection continues to grow. Spanish Civil War Posters were published by a variety of organizations representing both sides of the conflict, but best known, and most numerous, were those produced by the government of the Spanish Republic and its various divisions and allies -- government bodies, political parties, trade unions, and other groups ranging from Socialist, Communist and Anarchist parties to art collectives, youth groups, and aid organizations. Of the more than 230 posters in the ALBA series most were produced and published in Spain by groups that supported the cause of the Republic. But the series also includes posters published in the United States, Italy, Mexico, Cuba, France, and Germany, either in support of the Republican cause, or, in later years, to publicize commemorations, anniversaries, exhibits, film screenings, and other events relating to Spanish Civil War history. Series II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection (TAM Graphics 002), 1936-1938: This group of posters is part of the Library's general poster collection. It is an open collection, acquired by the library over many years, from many sources.
Existence and Location of Copies
Most of the images in Series II may be viewed online--both on-site and remotely--via the ARTstor website at http://library.artstor.org/library/welcome.html by researchers who are affiliated with New York University. Researchers not affiliated with New York University may view these images online only while visiting the Tamiment Library.
Custodial History
Series I: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, 1936-2003. The core group of posters in this group came to the Tamiment Library as part of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, which was acquired by New York University in 2001. Other posters have been donated since, and the collection continues to grow.
Series II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection (TAM Graphics 002), 1936-1938. This group of posters form part of the Library's general poster collection. It is an assembled collection, acquired by the library over many years, from many sources.
The accession number 1950.157 is associated with this collection.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
Political posters' essential role in propaganda and sustaining morale of both combatants and civilians during the Spain’s Civil War of 1936-1939 has been well-documented in numerous books, exhibitions and catalogs. They were published by organizations representing both sides of the conflict, but best known, and most numerous, were those produced by the government of the Spanish Republic and its allies. These posters, published by political parties, labor unions and federations, and other entities, reflect deep divisions between the Republic's supporters -- ranging from the Socialist, Communist and Anarchist parties, to smaller splinter groups, collectives, aid organizations, youth groups, and regional militias.
Their striking graphic qualities and propaganda value, which observers noted during the War and have attracted art historians and collectors ever since, served very practical ends. Posters were aimed at, and competed for the attention of, viewers who were often literally under fire. The large numbers of posters that were produced (an estimated 1,500-2,000 posters appeared, many printed in editions of 3,000 to 5,000, in the brief period 1936-1939) made them “an essential part of the visual landscape” of the war, as one scholar has observed. Posters were also used to garner support for the Republic, and for the International Brigades of volunteers that came to its defense, in other countries around the world.
In the years after the War’s end, posters continued to be used to publicize history of the Republic and its legacies. Posters protested the authoritarian rule of General Franco (whose rebel forces had defeated the Republic), memorialized the War and the Republic, advocated for refugees and veterans, and eventually celebrated the return of a democratically-elected government to Spain after Franco’s death in 1975.
Sources:
La guerra civil en 2000 carteles: república-guerra civil-posguerra, compiled by Jordi Carulla and Arnau Carulla. [Alternate title: Guerra civil en dos mil cartels] Barcelona: Postermil, 1997.
The visual front: posters of the Spanish Civil War from UCSD’s Southworth Collection. (http://orpheus.ucsd.edu/speccoll/visfront/vizindex.html)
Scope and Content Note
This collection is comprised of two separate, but related, groups of Spanish Civil War posters held by the Tamiment Library. Although the two groups are stored separately, and are of different provenance, their closely related contents warranted bringing them together in a single collection guide. Researchers should note the item numbers of any posters requested, since these numbers reflect the locations of individual posters. Each poster has an item number consisting of two letters, followed by a number. The two letters denote the country in which the poster was produced: CU=Cuba, DD=Germany, ES=Spain, FR=France, IT=Italy, MX=Mexico, US=United States. Poster locations are indicated by flat file case (FFC) number and folder number.
Series I: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Collection, 1936-2003. is divided into four sub-series, as follows: Subseries I:A: Civil War Era: Spain, 1936-1938. Subseries I:B: Civil War Era: Other Countries, 1937-1943. Subseries I:C: Post-Civil War Era: Spain, 1976-1997. Subseries I:D: Post-Civil War Era; Other Countries, 1966-2003.
The majority of the posters in this series were produced and published in Spain by organizations (political parties and their subgroups, national regional and local government agencies, military authorities, trade unions, aid organizations, collectives, etc.) supporting the cause of the Spanish Republic, but the collection also includes posters published during the war years and after in the United States, Italy, Mexico, Cuba, France, and Germany. Identified creators of the posters include thirty-three artists, the best-known of whom are Jose Bardasano, Josep Renau, and the Hungarian-American, Hugo Gellert. About half the poster artists are not identified.
Civil War era posters were published by a wide variety of organizations, including, but not limited to: the Socialist-leaning Union General de Trabajadores (UGT); the anarchist Confederación Nacional del Trabajo (CNT) and Juventudes Libertarias; Partido Comunista de España; Front Popular de Catalunya; Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid; El Grupo Sindical Socialista de Radiocomunicacion lleguara a la URE. a la Victoria; Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes, UGT; and the parallel (and rival) aid organizations, Socorro Rojo Internacional (aka International Red Aid, sponsored by the Communist International) and Socorro Rojo de España (sponsored by the Partido Obrero de Unificación Marxista, [POUM]). Organizations based outside of Spain include the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade and the Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee.
The post-Civil War era posters, also divided between those produced in Spain and in other countries, were produced to commemorate anniversaries; to honor the veterans; and to publicize film screenings, theatrical performances, conferences, and other events relating to Spanish Civil War history.
Series II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection (TAM Graphics 002), 1936-1938. This is an open collection, acquired by the library over many years, from many sources. Subjects and artists represented are similar to those in Subseries I:A.
Arrangement
Items are arranged alphabetically by artist's surname, followed by items arranged alphabetically by title (posters for which the artist’s name is unknown).
Organized into two series: I:Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, 1936-2003; II: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Tamiment Library Poster Collection, 1936-1938.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Posters.; Spain.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Posters.; Confederación Nacional del Trabajo (Spain); Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy; Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985; Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee; Federación Ibérica de Juventudes Libertarias; Calandin, José; Clusellas, Enric; Espert, José Luis; Amster, Mauricio, 1907-; Bardasano, José; Bon, 1886-1967; Briones Martinez, José; Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes; Juventudes Libertarias (Spain); Renau, Josep, 1907-1982; Melendreras, Emeterio.; Unión General de Trabajadores de España; Socorro Rojo de España; Xirinius Juez, Juame.; Vila Gimeno, Vicente, 1908-2009; Nicome Jos Gomez; Front Popular de Catalunya; Obiols, Ricard.; Goñi, Lorenzo.; International Red Aid; Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid; Puyol, Ramón.
- Series I: Spanish Civil War Posters from the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Collection, 1936-2003.
  - Subseries I:A: Civil War Era: Spain, 1936-1938.
    - Alumá. “Visca l’exèrcit popular. Setmana de l’exèrcit popular.” [Published by] Front Únic de Dibuixants U.G.T.-C.N.T. Imprint “I.G. Seix i Barral E.C. - Barcelona.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC 6-3, Folder 14, Item ALBA-ES 111)
    - Amster, Mauricio. “Luchan contra el fascismo combatiendo la ignorancia.” [Published by] Ministerio de Instrucción Pública, las Milicias de la cultura, Cartilla escolar antifascista. Imprint “Graficas Valencia, intervenido U.G.T.-C.N.T.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 31)
    - Anonymous. “Batallon de Pontoneros. Comandancia de Obras y F[ortifica]cion.” [Published by] Estudio de la Comandancia. Imprint “Unión Poligrafica, C.O. - Madrid.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC 6-3, Folder 14, Item ALBA-ES 89)
    - Anonymous. “La Fortificación arma de vanguardia.” [Published by] Estudio de la Comandancia. Imprint “Unión Poligrafica, C.O. - Madrid.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC 6-3, Folder 14, Item ALBA-ES 90)
    - Bardasano, José. “!!Alerta!! [C]e hará útil y fuerte para la defensa.” Imprint “Ortega - intervenido - U.G.T. - C.N.T. - Valencia.”, Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 33)
    - Bardasano, José. “Españoles: por la independencia y la libertad de nuestra patria !100.000 voluntarios!” [Published by] Partido Comunista de España. Imprint “S[ocie]dad Gral. de Publicaciones (E.C.) - Borrell, 243-249, Barcelona.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 34)
    - Bardasano, José. “Mando único en el transporte al servicio de la guerra.” [Published by] Partido Comunista de España. Imprint “S[ocie]dad Gral. de Publicaciones (E.C.) - Borrell, 243-249, Barcelona.” H: x W: 27.5 inches. (2 copies), Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 32)
    - Bardasano, José. “Su Excelencia el Presidente de la República ha dicho: ...cuando yo hablo de mi nación.” Imprint “Ortega, Valencia. Control U.G.T.-C.N.T.” H: 25.5 x W: 34.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 10, Item ALBA-ES 91)
    - Bon. “El Comisario alma y guia de nuestro ejercito. !!La Victoria es nuestra!!” [Published by] Comisariado General de Guerra, Comision de Propaganda, Inspeccion Centro. Imprint “Sindicato de Profesionales de las Bellas Artes, U.G.T. Rivadeneyra C.[O.-, 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 35)
    - Cabana y Contreras. “Ayudad a Madrid sufrido y heroico.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid, Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Lito - Martin - U.G.T. Madrid.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., [c. 1937] (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 36)
    - Calandin, José. “Colectivistas del Campo! El Ministro de Agricultura os ayuda.” [Published by] Instituto de Reforma Agraria”. Imprint “Graficas Valencia, intervenido U.G.T. C.N.T.” H: 46 x W: 31 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 37)
    - Calzada, C. “Columna España Libre os llama ingresad.” [Published by] Control - U.G.T. Imprint “‘LYF’ Madrid. To. 43606.” H: 39.4 x W: 27.2 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 38)
    - Clusellas, Enric. “IIIer U.G.T. Congrés de la U.G.T. a Catalunya. Sindicats de cara a la guerra. Dies 13, 14, 15, i 16 de Novembre a Barcelona.” [Published by] U.G.T. Imprint “Arts Grafiques Thomas - Industria Collectivitzada. Barcelona.” H: 19.7 x W:, 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 39)
    - Durbán Muixí. “10 Articles de primera necessitat.” [Published by] Generalitat de Catalunya, Conselleria de Proveiments. Imprint “Graf-Ultra S.A. Corcega 220 - Barna.” H: 27.5 x W: 19 inches., 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 4, Item ALBA-ES 40)
    - Espert, José / Briones, José. “!No pasarán! 7 de Noviembre, Madrid.” [Published by] Subsecretaria de Propaganda, Delegación en Madrid. Imprint “Sindicato de Profesionales de las Bellas Artes - U.G.T. Graficas Reunidas U.H.P. Madrid.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 41)
    - Gellert, Hugo. “5. In unity there is strength.” H: 17 x W: 11 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 42)
    - Gellert, Hugo. “8. Peace - Jobs - Democracy.” Brandeis. H: 17 x W: 11 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 43)
    - Girón. “1º Ganar la guerra.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid. Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes U.G.T. Graficas Reunidas, U.H.P. Madrid.” H: 39.4 x W: 27.6 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 44)
    - Goñi, Lorenzo. “I tú? Que fas per la Victoria?” (top half). [Published by] Front Popular de Catalunya. Imprint “Fotolitografia Barguño E.C. Barcelona.” H: 29 x W: 40 inches. (2 copies), Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 45)
    - Goñi, Lorenzo. “I tú? Que fas per la Victoria?” (bottom half). [Published by] Front Popular de Catalunya. Imprint “Fotolitografia Barguño E.C. Barcelona.” H: 29 x W: 40 inches.), Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 46)
    - Henn. “La victoria impone a quienes la desean sacrificios considerables, y uno de estos, que no puede ser descuidado si no queremos comprometerla, es el de producir más.” [Published by] F.G.E. Editado por el Comite Nacional. Imprint “Grafos - E.C. – Barna.” (2 copies), 1938 (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 50)
    - Henn. “Obreros producir más.” [Published by] F.E.I.F.T.A. Editado por el Comite Nacional. Imprint “Grafos [- E.C. -] Barna.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., 1938 (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 49)
    - Henn. “Salvad la producción!” [Published by] Editado por el Comite Nacional. Imprint “Grafos, E.C. – Barna.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., 1938 (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 47)
    - Henn. “Voy a luchar por tu porvenir.” [Published by] Editado por el Comite Nacional. Imprint “Grafos, E.C. – Barna.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., 1938 (Drawer FFC: 6-1, Folder 5, Item ALBA-ES 48)
    - Kantos. “Lo primero es ganar la guerra.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid, Delegacion de Propoganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato de Professionales de la Bellas Artes U.G.T. Lito Martin. U.G.T. - Madrid.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches. (2 copies), Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 51)
    - Lau (Nicolau Miralles Garcia.) “Regions i comarques. Octubre 1936.” [Published by] Conselleria d’Economia, Generalitat de Catalunya. Imprint “I.G. Seix i Barral, Empresa Col- lectivitzada – Barcelona.” H: 49 x W: 35 inches. [Duplicate of: TAM-ES 50.0-1[0], copy 1 of 2] (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 64)
    - M. “!Campesino! La tierra socializada es la mejor garantia de tu libertad.” [Published by] Juventudes Libertarias, Comite Peninsular, Madrid. Secretaria de Propaganda. Imprint “Helios Artes Graficas, Duque de Sexto, 32. Madrid U.G.T.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches, Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 52)
    - Más, R. “La ignorancia es arma del fascismo. Joven: ingresa en !!alerta!!” Imprint “Ortega - intervenido - U.G.T.-C.N.T. – Valencia.” H: 27.5 x W: 39 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 53)
    - Más, R. “Mañana podrà necesitarte. Joven: ingresa en !!Alerta!!” Imprint “Ortega - Intervenido U.G.T.-C.N.T. – Valencia.” H: 27 x W: 39 inches., 1936 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 54)
    - Melendreras, Emeterio. “Todas las milicias fundidas en el ejereito popular.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid, Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes, U.G.T. Rivadeneyra C.O.- Madrid.” H: 44.5 x, Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 57)
    - Melendreras, Emeterio. “Todos con un pensamiento único: Ganar la guerra, sin lo cuan se derrumbarán las conquistas de nuestra nueva República.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid, Delegacion de Propaganda y PrensaImprint “Sindicato Profesi, Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 55)
    - Melendreras, Emeterio. “Obreros de la construccion: alistaos en los Batallones de Fortificacion.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa, Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes, U.G.T. Gráficas Reunidas, U.H., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 56)
    - Molina. “Crim!...” [Published by] Secors Roig de Catalunya, S[ocorro] R[oio] I[nternacional]. Imprint “Fotolitografia Barguño E.C. Barcelona” H: 38 x W: 27.5 inches., c. 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 58)
    - Molina. “Front unic de la Solidaritat.” [Published by] Socors Roig de Catalunya, S[ocorro] R[oio] I[nternacional]. Imprint “Fotolitografia Barguño E.C. Barcelona.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches., 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 59)
    - Moro. “El Grupo Sindical Socialista de Radiocomunicacion lleguara a la U.R.E. a la Victoria.” [Published by] U.R.E. Imprint “Litografia LYF, Control U.G.T.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches. (3 copies), 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 6, Item ALBA-ES 60)
    - Obiols, Ricard. “Alerta!! Vigila a los que escuchan las radios facciosas y propagan noticias falsas.” [Published by] Sindicat de Porters U.G.T. H: 19 x W: 13.5 inches. (3 copies), Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 61)
    - Oliver. “La garra del invasor italiano pretende esclavizarnos.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid, Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa, [n.d] Imprint “Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes U.G.T. Rivadeneyra C.O. - Madrid.” H: 39 x W: 27 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 62)
    - Padial. “Acógela!” [Published by] Socorro Rojo de España. Imprint “Lit. S. Dura Socializada U.G.T. C.N.T. Valencia.” H: 31.5 x W: 22 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 63)
    - Parilla. “1º ganar la guerra. !Menos palabras vanas!” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid. Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato Professionales Bellas Artes, U.G.T. Rivadeneyra C.O.- Madrid” H: 39 x W: 27 inches. (2 copies), 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 67)
    - Parilla. “El ejercito popular es el ejercito de la Republica.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid, Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato Profesionales Belles Artes U.G.T. Rivadeneyra C.O. - Madrid.” H: 39 x W: 27.5 inches. (2 copies), Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 68)
    - Parilla. “Hogar del combatiente. La higiene, la cultura y la distracción sana acabaran con los vicios.” [Published by] Comisariado General de Guerra, Comision de Propaganda, Inspeccion Centro. Imprint “Sindicato de Bellas Artes U.G.T. Graficas Reunidas., 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 66)
    - Parilla. “Los Internacionales unidos a los Españoles, luchamos contra el invasor.” [Published by] Voluntarios Internacionales de Libertad, Ediciones de las Brigadas Internacionales. Imprint “Lit. Cromo, Madrid. Sindicato de Profesionales de las Bellas., 1937 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 69)
    - Parrilla. “Silencio en la retaguardia.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa de Madrid, Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes, U.G.T. Lit. E. Fernandez U.G.T. Gonzalo de Cordoba 17 - Madrid.” H: 38.6 x W:, Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 65)
    - Pedrero. “El generalisimo.” [Published by] Junta Delegada de Defensa, Delegacion de Propaganda y Prensa. Imprint “Sindicato Profesionales Bellas Artes, U.G.T. Rivadeneyra U.G.T. - Madrid.” H: 38.6 x W: 27.2 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 7, Item ALBA-ES 70)
    - Pico[lo]. “La joventut defensarà Catalunya. Diada de la joventut 14-21 de Marc.” [Published by] F[ederacion] J[oventut]. H: 27.5 x W: 19.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 71)
    - Puyol, Ramón. “El Acaparador.” [Published by] S[ocorro] R[ojo] I[nternacional]. Imprint “Ortega - intervenido, U.G.T.-C.N.T.-Valencia.” H: 34.5 x W: 25 inches., 1936 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 73)
    - Puyol, Ramón. “El Bulista.” [Published by] S[ocorro] R[ojo] I[nternacional]. Imprint “Ortega - intervenido, U.G.T.-C.N.T.-Valencia.” H: 34.5 x W: 25 inches., 1936 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 74)
    - Puyol, Ramón. “El Izquierdista.” [Published by] S[ocorro] R[ojo] I[nternacional]. Imprint “Ortega - intervenido, U.G.T.-C.N.T.-Valencia.” H: 34.5 x W: 25 inches., 1936 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 72)
    - Puyol, Ramón. “El Pesimista.” [Published by] S[ocorro] R[ojo] I[nternacional]. Imprint “Ortega - intervenido, U.G.T.-C.N.T.-Valencia.” H: 34.5 x W: 25 inches., 1936 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 75)
    - Puyol, Ramón. “El Rumor. !Guerra a muerte al rumor! Que intenta destrozar nuestra moral y nuestra unión.” [Published by] S[ocorro] R[oio] I[nternacional]. Imprint “Ortega - intervenido, U.G.T.-C.N.T. - Valencia.” H: 34.5 x W: 25 inches., 1936 (Drawer FFC: 6-3, Folder 10, Item ALBA-ES 112)
    - Reinoso. “No tireis los trapos viejos. Pues con ellos se fabricaran telas de abrigo para nuestros defensores.” H: 26 x W: 17.5 inches., Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 76)
    - Renau, Josep. “El Comisario, nervio de nuestro ejercito popular.” [Published by] Partido Comunista. Imprint “Graficas Valencia intervenido U.G.T. C.N.T.” H: 27 x W: 39.5 inches. (2 copies), Undated (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 77)
    - Renau, Josep. “Victoria. Hoy mas que nunca” (left half). [Published by] Sub[secretaria] [de] Pro[paganda]. Imprint “Barcelona, Graf[icas] Ultra S.A. Córega, 220. Barna.” H: 40 x W: 27.9 inches. (2 copies, 1938 (Drawer FFC: 6-2, Folder 8, Item ALBA-ES 78)